<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-16T19:24:04+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">David Virschi’s Blog</title><subtitle>David Virschi's Blog
</subtitle><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">No man, no fish, only sea…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/13/no-man-no-fish-only-sea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No man, no fish, only sea…" /><published>2022-08-13T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2022-08-13T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/13/no-man-no-fish-only-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/13/no-man-no-fish-only-sea.html">&lt;p&gt;I have finished the book and the ending is inspired by a real life event of the author, this is why I kind of knew how it would end. 
The idea I extract from this: I merely find it interesting the value of a trophy or a deed done, the same way it’s value is merely personal and yet connect to the outside world.
What value does a personal achievement have if you live in a cave and have never interacted with another human being? It’s a question without an answer because I can only imagine
seeking no such values when all alone with nature and animals. The old man remains with a respectable story known by those important to him. If I were to imagine the story after the end is the old man and the boy fishing
once more and no more bad luck could fall upon them. Only good days ahead and no story to tell, remaining only something personal, but still meaningful. Same with this blog, what I have after this is more
than a simple blog. I learned to write, to discipline myself and to think not only for myself, but how I am seen by myself in 3rd person and how others see me. Somehow connecting thoughts in the inefficiency of writing
about fragments of a book and fragments of random ideas that fly in my head, trying to order them all in this blog. What I remain with is the wish to talk to whoever reads this blog and to develop a connection, or 
an idea.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">I have finished the book and the ending is inspired by a real life event of the author, this is why I kind of knew how it would end. The idea I extract from this: I merely find it interesting the value of a trophy or a deed done, the same way it’s value is merely personal and yet connect to the outside world. What value does a personal achievement have if you live in a cave and have never interacted with another human being? It’s a question without an answer because I can only imagine seeking no such values when all alone with nature and animals. The old man remains with a respectable story known by those important to him. If I were to imagine the story after the end is the old man and the boy fishing once more and no more bad luck could fall upon them. Only good days ahead and no story to tell, remaining only something personal, but still meaningful. Same with this blog, what I have after this is more than a simple blog. I learned to write, to discipline myself and to think not only for myself, but how I am seen by myself in 3rd person and how others see me. Somehow connecting thoughts in the inefficiency of writing about fragments of a book and fragments of random ideas that fly in my head, trying to order them all in this blog. What I remain with is the wish to talk to whoever reads this blog and to develop a connection, or an idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The end</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/12/the-end.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The end" /><published>2022-08-12T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/12/the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/12/the-end.html">&lt;p&gt;In the blog before the end I will talk about nothing but as if it were the last blog and that’s a lie.
I could say that a beginning, a middle and an end, that is very simple in it’s narrative structure, can be a beautiful thing, can be satisfying, but I wonder.
What will I write if I end it here, what will happen if I go beyond the end and keep on plotting this scheme, sometimes being bored with the usual narrative in movies stories and the like. Sure, even something that has a predictable storyline, where you can guess when what will happen, can be fufilling, but why does it seem to be such an often thing?
You can seek inspiration from everything and create something original, being careful of the fine line between originality and commonness, this is quite possible. Yet why does almost every fantasy story with goblins and dragons and elves and orcs and knights and the like, medieval or futuristic, all inspire from the one thing, the one ring? Like I said in the last blog post, knowing nothing can be a very good thing when you try to create something. Having no inspiring figure, you can only rely on yourself and your own experiences which will always be unique. If I were a scientist and couldn’t find an alternative to a problem I couldn’t solve, I would seek help from somebody who knows nothing about science or math. 
If I were an artist I would seek inspiration from the simplest of things or from logic or from a non-artist. A person who knows nothing about anything can truly be the only one that
can look outside the box. Logic and pure intuition might be sides of the same coin. Being foolish might be the best way to solve and unsolvable problem, doing things that make no sense
might be the answer to originality.
But this blog isn’t about all that. I just want to see what happens when the main story ends and the plot is culminated, what happens to the characters and the world after that.
And so I haven’t read the last pages of the book yet, but I can predict what will happen. This makes me feel good that I will get there in the end and see for myself how the story culminates.
It also makes me slightly feel that I wanna leave the ending to my imagination and never finish the book, but I promised to myself, so I will. 
What would happen to the old man at sea? He might succeed in catching the biggest fish or he might not. What this part of the story shows the best is that it’s not the ending that matters most, it’s also just the try and the trial. The will or the method to oblige yourself do something no matter how much time it takes and in the end you know you tried your best for what matters to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">In the blog before the end I will talk about nothing but as if it were the last blog and that’s a lie. I could say that a beginning, a middle and an end, that is very simple in it’s narrative structure, can be a beautiful thing, can be satisfying, but I wonder. What will I write if I end it here, what will happen if I go beyond the end and keep on plotting this scheme, sometimes being bored with the usual narrative in movies stories and the like. Sure, even something that has a predictable storyline, where you can guess when what will happen, can be fufilling, but why does it seem to be such an often thing? You can seek inspiration from everything and create something original, being careful of the fine line between originality and commonness, this is quite possible. Yet why does almost every fantasy story with goblins and dragons and elves and orcs and knights and the like, medieval or futuristic, all inspire from the one thing, the one ring? Like I said in the last blog post, knowing nothing can be a very good thing when you try to create something. Having no inspiring figure, you can only rely on yourself and your own experiences which will always be unique. If I were a scientist and couldn’t find an alternative to a problem I couldn’t solve, I would seek help from somebody who knows nothing about science or math. If I were an artist I would seek inspiration from the simplest of things or from logic or from a non-artist. A person who knows nothing about anything can truly be the only one that can look outside the box. Logic and pure intuition might be sides of the same coin. Being foolish might be the best way to solve and unsolvable problem, doing things that make no sense might be the answer to originality. But this blog isn’t about all that. I just want to see what happens when the main story ends and the plot is culminated, what happens to the characters and the world after that. And so I haven’t read the last pages of the book yet, but I can predict what will happen. This makes me feel good that I will get there in the end and see for myself how the story culminates. It also makes me slightly feel that I wanna leave the ending to my imagination and never finish the book, but I promised to myself, so I will. What would happen to the old man at sea? He might succeed in catching the biggest fish or he might not. What this part of the story shows the best is that it’s not the ending that matters most, it’s also just the try and the trial. The will or the method to oblige yourself do something no matter how much time it takes and in the end you know you tried your best for what matters to you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fish n men</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/11/fish-n-men.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fish n men" /><published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/11/fish-n-men</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/11/fish-n-men.html">&lt;p&gt;The middle 19 pages are a fishing game. I divert from the plot with ambiguity so as to not spoil anything. To be sincere, and sincerity dwells in writting; I find it harder to write about the middle of a book, or I might have a bland day (but that also isn’t true). I might just be filling a blog with my thoughts due to lack of ideas, maybe this is what Fyodor always does in the beginning of his books, just that it’s a normality. I could talk about the lack of salt, yet the old man is kind of a sweety. I’m probably ruining Hemingway’s intentions. I could say that it has very much of the same happenings or “as we ferret further into the story, in to the end, we notice a shift”.
As I try to dicipline myself, so does the story. Parallels can be found anywhere, yet, oddly, nowhere as uninteresting as here. You can always wonder what would happen if a teacher gave you a homework, and the homework is an essay about a book, and you do the homework, and you show some things of the sort I’m webbing about in here.
So I digress; the story makes it harder and harder to let go, as if it wasn’t hard enough for such a short book. We are at sea and I’m just fishing for the biggest word (up). I just can’t wait to read the next pages. Believe all is true.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">The middle 19 pages are a fishing game. I divert from the plot with ambiguity so as to not spoil anything. To be sincere, and sincerity dwells in writting; I find it harder to write about the middle of a book, or I might have a bland day (but that also isn’t true). I might just be filling a blog with my thoughts due to lack of ideas, maybe this is what Fyodor always does in the beginning of his books, just that it’s a normality. I could talk about the lack of salt, yet the old man is kind of a sweety. I’m probably ruining Hemingway’s intentions. I could say that it has very much of the same happenings or “as we ferret further into the story, in to the end, we notice a shift”. As I try to dicipline myself, so does the story. Parallels can be found anywhere, yet, oddly, nowhere as uninteresting as here. You can always wonder what would happen if a teacher gave you a homework, and the homework is an essay about a book, and you do the homework, and you show some things of the sort I’m webbing about in here. So I digress; the story makes it harder and harder to let go, as if it wasn’t hard enough for such a short book. We are at sea and I’m just fishing for the biggest word (up). I just can’t wait to read the next pages. Believe all is true.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The aged man and the sea, without the boy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/10/the-aged-man-and-the-sea-without-the-boy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The aged man and the sea, without the boy" /><published>2022-08-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2022-08-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/10/the-aged-man-and-the-sea-without-the-boy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/10/the-aged-man-and-the-sea-without-the-boy.html">&lt;p&gt;From the last blog I was told how Heminway has died and so in the next 19 pages and further I might be influenced in perspective, but I also gained this new perspective where sometimes going in blind and being surprised in life is better than to know it all. Everybody should learn to be naive, to be afraid and to seek foolishness. Nothing wrong with that.
When reading these pages it felt like no time at all has passed. You might not wonder what an old man at the sea can have happen and yet there is suspense, there is lick of the lip.
I notice a loneliness in the need for someone and the repeated self given words, wimping for the boy that is not here, yet he knows what he has to do, what he was born to do and which is the right way to die. Strong but simple reminders push the reading forward, they make you feel sure and steady. There is serenity in the story telling, a future that could be foretold. 
Finding it very interesting how, if it tries to guess, it can find clues about what a human is thinking, bits about what was in somebody’s life, his/her perspective of some things, silluettes of some meaningful people; through the work, the art or the writtings of anyone. Simple details are easy to miss or even intentionally fabricated to make you feel
a certain way, everything can be intuitive and nothing can be certain.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">From the last blog I was told how Heminway has died and so in the next 19 pages and further I might be influenced in perspective, but I also gained this new perspective where sometimes going in blind and being surprised in life is better than to know it all. Everybody should learn to be naive, to be afraid and to seek foolishness. Nothing wrong with that. When reading these pages it felt like no time at all has passed. You might not wonder what an old man at the sea can have happen and yet there is suspense, there is lick of the lip. I notice a loneliness in the need for someone and the repeated self given words, wimping for the boy that is not here, yet he knows what he has to do, what he was born to do and which is the right way to die. Strong but simple reminders push the reading forward, they make you feel sure and steady. There is serenity in the story telling, a future that could be foretold. Finding it very interesting how, if it tries to guess, it can find clues about what a human is thinking, bits about what was in somebody’s life, his/her perspective of some things, silluettes of some meaningful people; through the work, the art or the writtings of anyone. Simple details are easy to miss or even intentionally fabricated to make you feel a certain way, everything can be intuitive and nothing can be certain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The boy, the old man and the sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/09/the-boy-the-old-man-and-the-sea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The boy, the old man and the sea" /><published>2022-08-09T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2022-08-09T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/09/the-boy-the-old-man-and-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misc/2022/08/09/the-boy-the-old-man-and-the-sea.html">&lt;p&gt;In this very first blog of mine and the very first personal project, I will try to express myself in a manner that I, myself, would find interesting when reading it; and fail miserably. I’ve read 25 page of “The old man and the sea” and now I will lay my opinions on the writer’s vision in the first quarter of this book. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
The first thing I noticed from the very first pages is the way this story is written, very descriptive, but very short phrases. This way of writing was sort of unsettling for me. The naration, that takes place in my head while learning about the characters and the world, is very jerky and gives the perect setting in this sort of simple world with the old man, the boy and the sea, almost making me read to myself as if I am reading to a little kid. The dialogue doesn’t refract from this, the characters answering each other in singular setences. It feels as if you’re giving me more than I am actually reading!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I honestly can’t wait to read the next part of this book tomorrow, to find out more about the meek and deceptively simple old man, the kind boy and what will happen out in this sea, in which the word “sea” alone can drift you very far into the mysterious light blue sky or the dark blue waters that can hide wonders or terrors and to 
never be able to know what a story can lay for you. Thinking and writing about this book, which should be read in one go, while also taking a tormeting break every 20 or so pages, makes me feel maudlin and enhances the “real” of the setting Hemingway tries to convey. Empathizing with the “refresh” the old man feels every day even if he didn’t catch any fish, is heart-warming.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Virschi</name><email>davidvirschi@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html">In this very first blog of mine and the very first personal project, I will try to express myself in a manner that I, myself, would find interesting when reading it; and fail miserably. I’ve read 25 page of “The old man and the sea” and now I will lay my opinions on the writer’s vision in the first quarter of this book. The first thing I noticed from the very first pages is the way this story is written, very descriptive, but very short phrases. This way of writing was sort of unsettling for me. The naration, that takes place in my head while learning about the characters and the world, is very jerky and gives the perect setting in this sort of simple world with the old man, the boy and the sea, almost making me read to myself as if I am reading to a little kid. The dialogue doesn’t refract from this, the characters answering each other in singular setences. It feels as if you’re giving me more than I am actually reading! I honestly can’t wait to read the next part of this book tomorrow, to find out more about the meek and deceptively simple old man, the kind boy and what will happen out in this sea, in which the word “sea” alone can drift you very far into the mysterious light blue sky or the dark blue waters that can hide wonders or terrors and to never be able to know what a story can lay for you. Thinking and writing about this book, which should be read in one go, while also taking a tormeting break every 20 or so pages, makes me feel maudlin and enhances the “real” of the setting Hemingway tries to convey. Empathizing with the “refresh” the old man feels every day even if he didn’t catch any fish, is heart-warming.</summary></entry></feed>